

Charles Alfred Koenig

Nationality: Liberian (+231) 770726935

(+90) 5338766422

Date of birth: 04/07/1999

Gender: Male

Email address: <u>koenigalfredcharles@gmail.com</u>

Email address: 210601045@rdu.edu.tr

Website: <u>kacharles.github.io/coursera-learn/mod3-solu/</u>

№ Whatsapp Messenger : +231770726935

№ Whatsapp Messenger : +90533876422

f Facebook: https://web.facebook.com/charles.koenig.94/

O Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/charles_alfred_koenig/

• Address: Gonyeli Mh., Livera Ozel Ogrenci Yurdu, Ataturk Caddesi, Lefkosa Abdi

Cavus Sokak, Walled City, Lefkosia, 99010 Lefkosia (Cyprus)

ABOUT ME

I am Charles Alfred Koenig and I am a Liberian, from West Africa. I am a graduate of the National Institute of IT (NIIT) with a professional diploma in software engineering from BlueCrest University College Liberia/NIIT and I hold a high school diploma from the Sr. Kathleen McGuire Memorial Catholic High School. I am a software engineer. I am specialized in web front-end development and UI design. I have good knowledge of the following programming languages that drive the development of the web namely: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, and Bootstrap. I have a good command of Microsoft Office tools and usage of the internet. I also have an average skill in mobile application development for the android platforms using Android Studio and the Java programming language. I am currently taking other web development courses on Coursera such as Building Web Application in PHP, and HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for web developers and etc. I am also enrolled at Rauf Denktas University in the TRNC(Turkish Republic of Northern Cyprus) and I am doing an undergraduate program in software engineering.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Private tutor

Self-Employed [09/05/2017 – Current]

City: Paynesville Country: Liberia

I am a private tutor. Although I have never taught for any institution or organization, I have conducted personal tutorials and study classes for students. Some of which I volunteered and some I got paid for. I love to teach. What I do in my study class is that I teach, make reviews, and evaluate the reviewing to see how much of what my students remember.

In addition to teaching, I provide practice work for students to do themselves. I understand that one learns best by doing.

I also do one-to-one or one-to-many mentoring providing simple tips and tricks for students to keep inspired and to learn more easily and effectively. I believe my calling is to impact people and I do this when I have the opportunity to share my thoughts.

Orange Mobile Money Agent

Orange GSM Company [03/15/2019 - Current]

City: Monrovia
Country: Liberia

I worked for over one year as an agent for Orange Liberia GSM company. What I did as an agent at Orange Liberia was deposit and withdraw Orange Mobile Money to and from Orange GSM subscribers. Other functions that I performed as an agent were to help Orange subscribers purchase electricity, pay television bills, purchase airtime, purchase data bundles, and other products and services using Orange Mobile Money.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Professional Diploma In Software Engineering

BlueCrest College Liberia/National Institue Of IT [09/20/2018 - 03/20/2021]

Address: Fish Market Road, Sinkor, Monrovia Old Road Junction, Tubman Boulevard, Monrovia, 50101 Monrovia (Liberia)

https://liberia.bluecrestcollege.com/

High School Diploma

Sr.Kathleen McGuire Memorial Catholic High School [09/04/2009 - 07/07/2018]

Address: Cooper Farm, Rehab, ELWA, Paynesville Liberia P.O, Box, 50101 Paynesville (Liberia)

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): English

Other language(s):

Turkish Language

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A1 SPOKEN INTERACTION A1

DIGITAL SKILLS

Microsoft Office Suit

Microsoft Office / Microsoft Word / Microsoft Excel / Microsoft Powerpoint

Google Tools

Google Docs

Social Media

Social Media / Instagram / Facebook

Web Design & Development(Front-End)

JavaScript, jQuery (basic level) / Basic knowledge of the Bootstrap framework / Web Development: HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript / Java Programming language

DRIVING LICENCE

 Driving Licence: A1
 09/01/2020 - 08/01/2022

 Driving Licence: A
 09/01/2020 - 08/01/2022

 Driving Licence: B1
 09/01/2020 - 08/01/2022

 Driving Licence: B
 09/01/2020 - 08/01/2022

HONOURS AND AWARDS

Certificate Of Appreciation

TRIBE (Technology Research In Business And Education) [09/04/2020]

Certificate of appreciation for contributing to TRIBE (Technology Research In Business And Education) YEBC (Young Entrepreneurship Boot Camp) program.

Certificate Of Participation

African Youth Fellowship [08/03/2019]

Certificate of participation for attending a career symposium held at the US Embassy in Monrovia.

Certificate Of Recognition

St. Andrew Lutheran Church [08/12/2018]

Certificate of recognition in respect of my immeasurable hard work and therefore recognized as the **most cooperative** youth of the year.

Certificate Of Participation

Smiling Faces Int'l [12/16/2017]

Certificate of participation for participating in Write Liberia 2017. Liberia's annual short story and poetry writing competition organized by Smiling Faces International.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Reading, Speaking, and Coding

First and foremost, I love to read, study and learn. It's said that the more you learn, the more you earn. For me, reading is life and I earned more from reading. I read not just to know, but to be inspired by great authors, and the same I do to inspire others. I define motivation as motive plus action. If there's no motive, there can be no action and nothing has ever been done without inspiration. I get mine from reading books.

I love also to write computer programs. I write programs to make websites and mobile applications.